My society, Singapore, is a city-state known for its robust economic performance and practical citizens. However, in the past decade, the state has made an effort to shed its uninteresting image, stepping up its efforts to develop the arts scene on many different fronts. Though the arts, music, and literature sectors in Singapore have benefitted from extensive government funding, I still believe there is more room for the arts scene in Singapore to grow, considering the vast advantages arts bring to society.Pragmatists argue that we should not do more to develop the arts as much has already been done and there are more pressing concerns. They contend that Singapore is vibrant as it is, and any more artistic development will impinge upon our robust economic performance. This may be valid if Singaporeans get so engrossed in the arts locally that we neglect the traditional pursuit of financial success. However, the point that they overlook is that the arts come hand-in-hand with our economic progress. Today, my society is still one that prizes pragmatism over 
creativity; with many asserting that investing any more in the arts is a waste of precious resources. The fact of the matter is that we should strive to become a country where our business perfectly complements the arts. Poets and writers such as Cyril Wong and Catherine Lim have yet to make it big internationally. If the state provides them with even more aid, they may be able to branch out more easily_ Given that we are a relatively young nation, our history and heritage may not seem as rich as some Western countries where there are the Sistine Chapel frescoes and the Mona Lisa. Therefore, the implication that we should not do more to develop the arts in Singapore should not be accepted as the truth.

The fact that the arts serve as a platform and a comfortable place for Singaporeans to wind down and self-reflect is compelling corroboration for us to develop it even further and take our arts scene to greater heights_ The government has already taken a huge step in fully providing museum entry for all citizens and permanent residents, hence proving the undeniable benefit of savouring the arts. Furthermore, on the top of the widely known Maslow's hierarchy of needs, there lies self-actualisation. Self-actualisation can be achieved through creating works of art and literature Rut in our fast-paced society today, one can barely find or make time for any creative juices to flow. More can be done to allow Singaporeans to understand that the benefits of the arts are indeed tangible_ It allows a photographer or artist to capture a moment of beauty that he would like to share with his people. The arts can perpetuate comfort, happiness, reassurance, and they are definitely not a 
meaningless endeavour. For many who wish to pursue Arts, they forgo it for educational qualifications that are perceived to be more practical and more likely to secure them a stable job. It is still the case today that a young student who loves painting, or is interested in literature, or is passionate about music will likely not pursue this interest due to the perception it does not pay well. Hence, while much has already been done to improve the Arts locally, it seems that it is necessary for even more to be done.

Another reason why more should be done to develop the arts is that the arts are a useful and deeply pervasive tool for advocating change. Advocacy art is the term for creative pieces that seek to point out flaws of a system or even to just voice one's opinions. The arts then become a way for the state to take the people's views into account, which the lifeblood of democracy. Such was the case when a blogger created comic strips depicting the late Lee Kuan Yew's supposedly authoritarian regime, which was immediately suppressed. More recently, professional videographers produced a video of opposition politician Ghee Soon Juan and his family, which was posted online. It painted a more humane and empathetic picture of him, a departure from how he has been portrayed as a monster for his radical political views. The artistic skill of videography greatly facilitated the goal of the video, which was to evoke feelings of relatability, sympathy and sometimes even pity among the viewers, the electorate of Singapore. The arts can be a useful tool to be wielded when we want to make a statement, and more should be done to allow the arts to expand people's horizons, rather than severely clamp down on them once they go against what the government stands for. Overall, it can be seen that it is necessary for more to be done in the local arts scene to help it grown and achieve an equal status with our financial arts scene to help it grown and achieve an equal status with our financial hub. Being a financially-driven country, it is all the more imperative we do more to fund the arts to perfectly complement our ever-increasing economic growth. We cannot let the dream of the arts scene being both a lucrative and fulfilling business remain elusive.
