In modern society, the demand for consumer and producer goods is soaring sky high. Globalisation has caused new trade routes to open between countless countries, putting even more strain on these firms to operate and keep up the pace with production. In light of these circumstances, it has become extremely difficult for firms to be ethical in their ways.Critics argue that in modern society, many activists and non-governmental organisations (NG0s) are paying more attention to the practices of these firms. One such organisation is Amnesty International, an NGO which advocates human rights, including those of workers. With this increased attention, there is more pressure for firms to be ethical_ One example is Fair Trade, which is an ethical practice. In Fair Trade companies, workers are paid fairly and production is carried out in an ethical manner, which is environmentally friendly and protects the rights of the workers. In modern society, people argue that there is much more pressure on companies to convert to ethical practices. However, these people fail to see the shortcomings of their arguments. While Fair Trade companies may seem like an ideal and utopian situation, and granted that there are a few large firms that carry out fair trade, the idea of all firms carrying out practices such as these is a pipe dream, especially in today's context. Due to the ethical production process, Fair Trade products have very high production costs and fairly low production rates. Firms these days simply cannot afford to lose productivity and capital in order to compete and stay relevant with their competitors in this fierce industry. Hence, while being morally ethical is an ideal situation for firms, today's society does not allow the situation to come true.

In modern society, production costs are soaring due to recent economic problems such as the Euro Crisis and China's economic slowdown. This 
poses a major problem to firms as high production costs represent lower profits, which lead to lower competitiveness in the market. It is absolutely essential for firms to seek out alternative methods of production that are cheaper. Unfortunately, in most cases, this means using unethical ways of operating. Dumping waste materials instead of treating them is a very well-known unethical practice that firms conduct. One famous case is the dumping of chemical waste by Chevron, a gas and energy producing company, in Ecuador in 2006, instead of properly treating it. This led to many cases of sickness due to exposure to the waste. This was done to cut production costs as treating the waste would have put a large dent in the company's capital, causing the company to potentially lose out to strong competitors in the energy industry, Due to the increasing cost of production, it is becoming increasingly difficult for firms to be ethical today.Another reason why firms are unable to be ethical today is the sharp rise in demand for goods_ With the development of western nations and the rise of BRIO, demand for both consumer and producer goods is rising. Globalisation and the development of aviation has made it even easier to import and export goods, putting even more pressure on firms to speed up production lines, This will inevitably lead to unethical practices from firms. One example is Mosanto, a firm specialising in GM food. The demand for  GM food has increased rapidly since it was created due to its alleged health benefits. To keep up with this demand. Monsanto has started overusing fertilisers on its crops, causing the soil and the environment to be damaged. It has even gone to the extent of suing and firing workers who used ethical and environmentally friendly ways to grow the crops as this meant slower growing crops. The increase in demand for goods around the world means that firms have to find ways to keep up with the demand, which will eventually lead to unethical ways of production.

Globalisation has opened up countless different choices for people all around the world. This includes different brands of goods. In light of this, it is becoming increasingly easy for firms to lose customers due to the wide is becoming increasingly easy for firms to lose customers due to the wide array of substitutes. This has resulted in a need for firms to come up with new ways to present and market their goods in order to convince consumers to buy their product and to stay relevant in the market For many companies, this could mean using unethical methods in advertising and marketing in desperate attempts to ruin more customers. One example is Philip Morris. an American cigarette company_ Philip Morris was found guilty of using children to advertise their cigarettes_ It also notoriously advertised tobacco addiction as beneficial to the country as it helps doctors earn higher salaries. Other companies such as Burger King and Calvin Klein caused controversies by using women dressed in skimpy clothing to advertise their products, which drew criticisms for objectifying women and abusing women's rights. Due to fierce competitors and the impact of globalisation. it is getting increasingly difficult for firms to be ethical in their practices. Due to globalisation and the rapid development of countries all around the world, firms have been used to the limit to produce goods at a rate where using ethical practices is simply not feasible to maintain competitiveness with others. Hence, it is definitely not realistic for one to be ethical, especially in modern society.