In today's rapidly globalising world, countries are embroiled in a rat race of getting ahead of one another in terms of economic growth and technological advancement. The 21st century has witnessed the rise of China, Russia and India, three of the largest countries in the world, and many claim that that the pax Americana of today will no longer stand tomorrow with the rise of China and other large countries as global hegemons. The term 'success' is one fraught with ambiguity — it means different things for different people and the meaning has evolved over time_ in this essay, success will be defined as improvements in the physical and emotional standard of living of people, economic growth, and technological progress. It is far too simplistic to say that geography is the sole determinant of a country's success, and certainly too absolute to claim that its people have totally no role in shaping the success of a country. The assumption of the question lies in the idea that geography plays a role at all, which it ostensibly does. While it can be argued that geography is one of the determinants of a country's success, the people of a country indubitably play a crucial role in the success of a country - their hard work and productivity improve the country's economic landscape and they catalyse change in terms of improving the overall quality of life in a country, but aside from a country's people and geography, the government of a country plays and incredible role in shaping the success of a country.

Proponents of the argument that geography is the only determinant of success and that people have no role to play postulate that geography provides a country with invaluable natural resource, and the sheer size of a country can enable it to wield immense power the global arena. Geography, no doubt, provides a country with natural resources that other countries may lack, which makes the country a valuable player in the global stage. For example, countries in the Middle East, such as Saudi Arabia, Kuwait and Iraq have vast oil reserves within their reach, and because oil plays such a pivotal role in technological progress and in many industries, many countries are dependent on the Middle Eastern countries for oil. The hegemony that these countries have over oil not only enables them to upgrade the facilities within their own country, but also enables them to maximise profits. For instance, during the Gulf War of 1991, Iraq had jacked up the prices of oil so much that it was practically ruinous for the world as the world is so dependent on oil, but it did enable Iraq to earn a hefty sum. The United Arab Emirates too, is one of the world's greatest shopping hubs, and its riches due to oil have enabled the creation of buildings such as the Bur] Khalifa. Thus, it can be seen that geography provides a country with indispensable natural resources that propel its economy_ In addition, the sheer size of a country enables it to wield immense power. For instance. China, today, due to its huge size, is able to drive the world's economy due to its population? This provides a country with a say in the balance of power in the world, which shifts towards them simply because of their size. Therefore, it can be seen that geography provides a country with power to propel a country's economy, and it tilts the balance of power in the world too.

However, it is ultimately the people who utilise the resources and size to make the country more productive, hence it is too far of a stretch to say that people have no role to play at all People, with their hard work, grit and determination, ultimately drive a country's economy. In the case of the USSR, for example, aside from the flaws in the communist system, the people were incredibly unmotivated, retying on vodka to release them from their stress and productivity levels were facing an all-time low, especially towards the end when the Soviet Union was about to collapse. It is indisputable that the Soviet Union was huge and had vast resources from its satellite states too, yet it could not achieve success for its people as economic growth dropped and people were unhappy. In contrast, Singapore , a 'tiny red dot', with no natural resources was able to achieve success for its people fifty years after achieving independence, and has indeed established itself as global financial and technological hub. Dubbed as one of the 'Asian Tigers', Singapore drives its economy on the sheer strength of its people, and although critics had contended in the past that Singapore's geography would be a limitation and an obstacle in its pursuit of success, Singapore proved these critics wrong, Singapore's first Prime Minister Lee Juan Yew had recognised the potential of its people and thus placed a lot of emphasis on education and the development of its people and hence achieved the success it desired in a short span of time.